Gang rule behind bars!
The Steel Jungle is a crime, drama film directed by Walter Doniger.
The tale of a young bookie, married to a beautiful woman who
goes to jail, and becomes involved with hoodlums.
Ed Novak, played by Perry Lopez.
Frances 'Francie' Novak, played by Beverly Garland.
Warden Bill Keller, played by Walter Abel.
Steve Marlin, played by Ted de Corsia.
Dr. Lewy, played by Kenneth Tobey.
Mrs. Archer, played by Allison Hayes.
The Steel Jungle is a 1956 American film noir crime drama directed by Walter
Doniger and starring Perry Lopez, Beverly Garland, and Walter Abel.
The film was directed and written by Walter Doniger.
Produced independently, the film was distributed by Warner Bros., and
theatrically released in the United States on March 10, 1956.
The film explores themes of prison, film noir, b movie, bookie.
The tone is dark and emotional.